if you don't already know rowers are a
great way to improve your cardiovascular
health while also toning your muscles at
the same time now one of my favorite
rowers on the market right now is
actually a three in one rower reformer
and strength trainer that's right I'm
talking about the lit method strength
machine this water rower really packs a
punch and I have a lot to break down for
you all today including the lit access
which is actually a separate product
consisting of resistance bands but can
be used in tandem with this machine so
kick back hang out with me for a little
bit as I break down both of these
products for y'all
yeah
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I have two separate products that
I'm going to be breaking down for y'all
the lit method strength machine and the
lit axis in this video I'm going to tell
you everything you need to know about
both of these products from the price
and the features as well as some pros
and cons and of course who should or
maybe should not buy these now before I
get going with all of that I gotta let
you know we've reviewed a ton of rowers
and resistance bands over on barbin.com
so if you want to browse our best list
go and search barbin best resistance
bands or barbin best rowers and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
okay so what do I like about the lit
method strength machine well first of
all I got to talk about the unboxing
process about 85 percent of this rower
was already assembled it only took about
10 to 15 minutes to do the rest myself
which is nice for you know obvious
reasons water Rovers like this one tend
to have a more natural feel than a rower
that uses electromagnetic resistance and
they're also mimicking being on an
actual open body of water which is
pretty cool but Rovers also you know
require about 80 to 85 percent of your
full body as you're working out so
you're really able to tone just about
all of your muscles while also getting a
cardio workout in at the exact same time
you are required to sign up for
membership to gain access to the
available classes that Lit has to offer
but it's only going to be about 25 bucks
a month which is cheaper than some of
the competition out there something
really cool here is that Lit actually
tosses in a three-month free trial with
your purchase which is really nice you
know you're really able to get a sense
for how the whole app works for all the
workout classes and everything and
really enjoy it and kind of see some
results and really figure out whether or
not you want to pay monthly for this
membership the classes themselves I
found to be really helpful you know the
really high energy whoever's instructing
your class is going to push you and
really try to get the most out of you
and really just makes it seem as if
you're right there in the room with them
which is really cool I also thought the
music that was in the classes was you
know a nice touch it's fresh up-to-date
music and I'm sure they're rolling out
new songs you know as Things become more
popular over time which is really nice
you'll notice you don't have a monitor
with this rower which I personally
really like that you know a lot of times
with products like this that feature a
built-in monitor that monitor is going
to get dated before the actual product
will at least in a lot of cases that's
true and you know with this it's really
nice you don't have to worry about that
so you do have a holder right here for
your phone or tablet whichever one you
want to use just kind of clamp it in and
you're good to go now that way like you
can always you know upgrade your phone
owner tablet whatever it is without
having to get you know a whole new
product which is really nice another
thing you're going to notice here with
this product is that there are no cords
whatsoever which is something that I
personally love you know I can take this
bad boy outside and do my workouts on a
pretty day which is something you can't
always do with cardio equipment you know
unless of course you have a super long
extension cord which is really nice you
also have Bluetooth capabilities right
here it's going to pair up with your
phone through the companion app which
I'm going to talk about in a little bit
and you're really able to track all of
your metrics which is really cool
[Music]
all right now let's break down a few
cons you may run into with the lit
method strength machine first of all we
got to talk about storage so this rower
is designed to be stored vertically
which is really nice but I personally
have not been able to do that well I've
tried and the water starts leaking out
of the actual drum right here so that
might not be the case with everybody you
know with every single specific rower
but it's something I've ran into so
definitely just be careful about that
since this is in fact a water rower it's
likely going to be louder than a rower
that uses electromagnetic resistance so
if you have any roommates you know
definitely keep that in mind as well
especially if you're working out early
in the morning or late at night another
thing you got to think about here is if
you're somebody like myself you have all
of your gear stashed in a garage you got
to worry about whether or not this rower
is going to freeze on you so it's been
pretty cold here in Nashville as of late
and I came out here one day and my water
was completely Frozen you know so if
you're not somebody who has all of your
gear stashed in a climate controlled
room definitely keep that in mind and
another thing I got to mention right
here I'm going to expand on this in just
a second is the money so there's three
different packages for you to choose
from but the most standard you know
basic package of this machine right here
is going to run you around 1800 bucks
yes there are some financing options but
that could be you know too expensive for
some people's budgets so definitely keep
that in mind as well
[Music]
all right so as promised let's talk
about some money and before I start
doing all that something I have to
mention is that with a product like this
absolutely bound to have a price change
so don't come barking at me if in the
not too distant future this is more
expensive than what I'm saying right now
okay so the standard package of the lit
method strength machine is going to run
you around 1800 bucks this is going to
include a 10 to 20 pound pair of
Resistance Bands a pair of ankle cuffs a
pair of D handles you'll get that three
month trial you know membership that I
was talking about and you're going to
get this phone or tablet holder if
you're interested in having more
accessories with your rower you can go
after that plus pack which is actually
going to toss in the lit access as well
so this is going to consist of the ankle
cuffs and the D handles but you're going
to get a pair of 15 pound resistance
bands and 30 pound resistance bands as
well as a strength bar for you to work
with your machine as well which I
actually don't have right now it's going
to run you around two grand and if you
want to make the most out of your
purchase you might want to go after the
pro pack which has everything the Plus
Pack has with the addition of a mat to
go underneath your strength machine and
a heart rate sensor now you do have
financing options for all three of those
packages plus you get a 30 day risk-free
trial of the product I really think the
lifetime warranty of the framework is a
nice touch and you get a five year
warranty on all the accessories and
remember once again you get a three
month free trial of the lit membership
which is really cool too
[Music]
thank you okay so since I was just
talking about the membership why don't
we go ahead and expand on that and I
don't think it's necessary to have a
membership but I think it's worth it so
once you create your profile you're
gonna have to decide you know how you
want to pay for that membership after
your three month free trial runs out and
once again shout out to lid because not
every single company provides a free
trial and especially one for this long
so that's just really cool once that
trial ends you know once again you have
to you know sign up to pay for that
monthly fee and you can either pay you
know 25 bucks a month or you can pay
yearly save some money for 240 bucks
okay so with your membership you're
gonna have unlimited access to all the
available live and on-demand classes on
the lit app I think it's really cool you
can have up to four additional people on
your membership that way everybody you
know has their own profile they're able
to track their own metrics and their own
progress workout history and everything
which is really cool all right so let's
expand on the classes and the companion
app lit once again you know you're going
to have unlimited access to over 2500
live and on-demand classes that are on
that app right now and that number is
continuing to grow so this app is
available to both iPhone and Android
users and the classes are going to range
from rowing to strength training to
Pilates and so much more alright so each
and every single one of these classes
are led by an instructor it's going to
start with a warm up you're going to get
into the actual workout then you'll kind
of cool off a little bit too which is
nice now throughout the classes you know
the app's going to pair up with your
equipment that way you can track all
your reps and if you have a heart rate
monitor it's going to also you know keep
track of the amount of calories you're
burning and give you a nice accurate
reading on that as well plus the app is
also going to track your overall
progress as well and it's going to
reward you with achievement badges for
Milestones you know such as classes
completed daily and weekly streaks
calories burned and even the amount of
weight you've lifted as well each class
has a quick description on what to
expect from that workout and it's going
to display what equipment you need for
that specific workout it's also really
cool that everything is broken down into
categories based on beginner
intermediate and expert level classes
that's really nice in my opinion you
know that way you don't wind up joining
a class that's too difficult you're in
over your head or maybe you join one on
accident that doesn't push you enough
okay so let's pump the brakes real quick
and transition into the lit axis just
really quick I want to break this down
this is a set of resistance bands as I
mentioned earlier and this is really
cool you're also going to get a pair of
ankle cuffs two D handles for you to
work out with and with those resistance
bands like I said you get two of them so
there's a 15 pound pair and a 30 pound
pair with but what's really cool about
these is that you can actually adjust
the resistance by moving further away
from your Anchor Point so you can anchor
these up you know just about anywhere
especially with the strap that's
included these also have Bluetooth
capabilities so right next to the
Carabiner there's a Bluetooth device I
guess you could call it that the bands
actually insert to and you know attach
to all you have to do is pull down on
the the band real quick and you'll see a
light pull up it's going to turn on it's
going to pair up with your app and
really track all of your reps time under
tension and everything and that's just
really cool to me so let's say you only
go after the lit access and you enjoyed
your three month free trial and you want
to have that membership fee well it's
only going to run you around 10 bucks a
month which is really nice and
resistance bands are great in my opinion
because it takes a lot of the stress off
of your joints when you're working out
and it still gives you a solid workout
so you know you need to go in a deload
week maybe you just kind of want to take
some stress off your body or maybe you
just don't want that stress in general
resistance bands are a great tool for
you to do that and like I said you know
you can adjust that resistance so the 30
pound pair of Vans you know each one can
actually go up to 100 pounds of
resistance so you attach them together
in whatever way you're really getting up
to 200 pounds of resistance so if you're
interested in just going after the lit
access this is going to run you around
160 bucks which is a really nice
budget-friendly alternative
[Music]
all right so in terms of the build with
the lit method strength machine they're
using a combination of Steel and
aluminum right here and it feels you
know really stable it feels really solid
on these feet they have right here which
is really nice it's about two feet
maybe a foot and a half wide or so and
it's about seven feet long right on the
money seven feet long so remember you
know if you're able to store yours
vertically remember I can't because it's
leaking right here it's going to be you
know seven feet tall so just definitely
keep that in mind it only weighs 70
pounds or so when it's empty and right
around 90 when it's full of water so
it's relatively easy for you to move it
around you know especially with these
wheels down here so that's nice as well
plus it has a really impressive weight
capacity of 400 pounds and in terms of
features obviously we got to talk about
this built-in rowing bar right here you
know
pretty simple straightforward it
definitely gets the job done there's no
type of you know grip pattern built into
it but it's definitely you know easy to
grip onto I really like the resistance
bands with the lit access you know it's
really nice how you can adjust that
resistance level just by simply moving
further away from your anchor Port point
which is really cool now the D handles
are really nice they have a rubber
coating but they feel really grippy in
my hands which I like for obvious
reasons you do have Bluetooth
capabilities and you have a Bluetooth
sensor built into the actual rubber
right here and remember with the lit
access you know you do have that
Bluetooth device whatever you want to
call it built in right next to those KR
that's also going to pair up
with your app and track all of your
metrics and everything I think this
phone slash tablet holder is really
unique you know I like that there's not
you know a massive monitor right here in
front of my face if I don't want to join
a workout class I just simply want to
hop on this bad boy and row for 10 15 20
minutes whatever you can easily do so
and you don't have to worry about any
you know outdated monitor in the next
couple of years which is really cool you
have four different levels to your
resistance with the actual rower right
here with the water which is really cool
four different levels each level
represents 10 pounds so you can go up to
40 pounds of resistance which is really
cool remember you do have the ankle
cuffs you can you know obviously put
them around your ankle that way you're
able to work on your legs and do
different workouts with those with their
resistance bands which is really nice I
also think it's really cool how they
tossed in this water pump right here it
might look a little funky it's really
easy to use you just toss one in in the
actual drum right here and have a bucket
of water you could use a hose if you
want to but you just simply squeeze on
this it's going to suck the water in and
bring it into the drum and reverse order
you know when it comes to taking the
water out you'll just squeeze it and the
water is going to come out for you use
it uses gravity I just think it's pretty
cool plus lit's also going to toss in
you know water treatment tablets and
it's basically a lifetime supply so you
really don't ever have to worry about
this water getting all nasty and you
don't have to change it for a really
long time either which is really nice
once again this is designed to be stored
vertically which I haven't been able to
do because my water starts leaking out
but you know if that isn't the case for
you Kudos but you know you have some
feet right here for it to rest on and
that's really nice there's not a
designated handle at the other end for
you to grab it and lift it up move it
around but it's relatively easy to do
it's not that big of a deal and we can't
forget about the music you know there's
tons of popular current up-to-date songs
that are going to be playing as you're
streaming your workouts and that's just
really nice too to kind of keep the
tempo up and going and one more thing
you know if you want to go after the
most basic package and just kind of
expand with your accessories and
everything over time you can do so so
you can get you know your heart rate
monitor you can get the strength bar
ankle cuffs there's an anchor there's a
bunch of stuff you can get even actual
cover for your machine so definitely
just check all that stuff out as well
[Music]
all right so let's go ahead and kind of
walk you guys around this and do a quick
demo just how everything works so I want
to start at the front obviously you got
your wheels right here it's really nice
for portability you also have your feet
right here that's for your vertical
storage and I'm going to show you guys
in a second I don't want to make too
much of a mess right now but I'm not
able to store this rower vertically
because the water is leaking out through
the seal right here now let's move a
little further up but as you can see you
have one of your anchor points right
here so you have five pairs you have you
know 10 total anchor points with this
row right here which is really nice you
know you can add two different workouts
with your resistance bands and
everything and that's cool now I really
like this phone slash tablet holder it's
really easy to use you know you just
take your phone kind of toss it in here
sometimes your phone wants to slide out
I don't have a tablet or else I'd be
using it right now for you guys but for
the most part you know you'll find a way
for it to stick now if you do have a
tablet it's really nice that Lit goes
ahead and they they kind of accommodate
for everybody and they have these you
know extenders right here it's really
simple you can just slide it in right
there and as you can see you know this
comes out way more than those other ones
do and this is gonna be really nice if
you have a tablet now you have a
basically like a strap right here and
that's going to be you know connected to
your built-in handle I haven't noticed
anything in terms of this coming off the
tracks I have seen some people talk
about it online but I think it's gonna
be really easy for you to put it back on
there now right here is obviously your
water drum
really simple process in terms of
filling it up you know you have your
little spot right here you can pour
water into or you can use that pump I
was showing you guys earlier and
right here well I got you here you have
your Bluetooth sensors it's gonna be
really nice you know it pairs up to the
lit app and it tracks you know all of
your reps and everything which is you
know really nice now on the back side
right here is your lit levels you have
four different ones depending on how lit
you want to be and this is just really
you know each number corresponds to 10
pounds so I have it on the four it's up
to 40 pounds of resistance and you know
30 2010 you know so on and so forth now
let's move a little further up you have
your foot holders I guess you could call
them right here seems pretty Universal
in size to me but you can always adjust
it you pull them out right here you can
slide it down or pull it up really
whatever you want to do it's nice and
secure I like the straps really easy to
put your foot in and tighten it up your
feet aren't going to come out while
you're working out and that's really
nice now this seat
slides really smooth as well as you can
see you know you can just kind of strap
in right here and this is what I like
about this product it's basically No
Nonsense you know you can just hop right
on in
get your feet all nice and comfy
whatever your comfort level is and you
can just get right to it now I mentioned
this earlier you know obviously this is
a water rower so it's probably going to
be a little louder than one with
electromagnetic resistance but you know
super simple to get going
foreign
and then I like this little holder right
here too that's really nice really nice
touch right there super easy to get back
out as well this is how the vertical
storage goes it's really easy to do it
but the problem for me at least is that
water starts dripping out down here and
that's something that we definitely
don't want so it's fine for me but for
some people it might be a little bit of
a bummer maybe even a little bit of a
turn off and it's just something you
need to keep an eye on and I gotta
highlight the lit access as well so a
nice little travel kit you know that
comes with your purchase and
everything's laid out nicely as well
nice and organized as you can see now
let's go ahead and start up top right
here this so this is your portable
anchor this is really nice you know you
can toss this around a post you know
your your bed frame you know whatever
and you can attach your carabiners in
right here now you also have two
different ankle cuffs which is really
nice they've got a nice padding on them
they feel pretty comfortable on your
feet and that's a nice touch too so
let's talk about these bands so right
here this is the 30 pound resistance
band and it's nice that you can you know
it's got a nice little bag right there
for each specific one and whenever you
have them you know you can always see 30
pounds right there so you know which one
you're working with now this side this
is your little Bluetooth area there's a
little light right here and I'll show
you you just pull a little bit
and that light's going to come on and
it's going to pair up with your app on
your phone so that's cool now you have
these carabiners got these hooks I
showed you there's a couple anchor
points up top
you've also got one right here one on
the very back and you have one right
here on the actual side of the seat so
that's cool now you can attach it right
here or further up whatever and you're
able to get you know even more
resistance to your workouts these D
handles nice little rubber coating right
here it's got a little bit of a pattern
to help you get you know a nice solid
grip and these guys you know you can
just attach them right here obviously
I've got it attached to the seat but you
can go ahead and attach that right there
and you're able to get all your workouts
in and these are just a really cool tool
you know you can spice things up some of
the workouts are going to have you
actually hop off of the rower bust these
bad boys out and you know have a little
bit of a tandem workout I guess you
could say and one more thing with these
resistance bands is that you know the
further you walk away from your Anchor
Point
the harder it's going to be so that
resistance is going to increase right so
this is the 30 pound pair right here you
know it can go up to 100 pounds of
resistance the further you walk away
from that Anchor Point if that makes
sense so that's pretty cool you know you
are able to have varying levels of
difficulty during your workouts
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the lit
method strength machine well I think
this is a great product for anybody who
wants to improve the overall Fitness
level so you're going to burn a ton of
calories with this bad boy but you're
also going to do some strength training
as well especially if you go for the lit
axis now this also has a bit of a
no-nonsense approach to it which is
something that I thoroughly enjoy you
know somebody like me you don't care to
have all the big touchscreen monitors
and you know all that stuff this is a
great product for you which leads me to
my next point you know if you want a
product where you don't have to pay for
a membership fee you know this is
probably going to be the one for you now
I definitely think it's worth it you
know there's a lot of benefits with the
streaming platform especially with
tracking your progress and everything
like that but if you want a
straightforward rowing machine this is
going to be one of your best options
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this product it really
just boils down to two different things
for me let's talk about the resistance
first yeah up to 200 pounds essentially
you know with the resistance bands and
everything but eventually you are going
to reach that Max resistance threshold I
guess you could say and that's something
you really wouldn't run into you know in
terms of strength training you know with
free weights so definitely just keep
that in mind and then really it's just
the money so you know the cheapest
version of the lit method strength
machine it's still going to run you
around 1800 bucks so it could fall out
of some people's budgets and that's just
going to be a reason for somebody not to
purchase this
[Music]
that's all I have for you guys today on
the lip method strength machine and the
lit access I think both of these are
really solid products they're versatile
they're Compact and they both really
pack a punch just remember the lip
method strength machine might wind up
being a little bit too expensive for
some people and eventually you can run
into that problem of a Max resistance
and it not being enough for you plus
gotta remember you know you might not be
able to store it vertically like it's
intended to do thanks for hanging out
with me everybody I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
break down everything you need to know
about both of these products as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com because we
have a written article about this review
all you gotta do is type in barbin lip
method strength machine review
everything's going to pull up for you
and you can find all the details and
everything that I discussed here today
I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
thank you